# María Alejandra Pérez

# UI / UX Designer with background in Engineering

UI / UX Designer with a passion for user-centric solutions and workflow optimization.

By efficiently researching and communicating with stakeholders and customers I design useful, honest, and accessible processes and products that understand the customer's struggles and motivations as well as the business needs.

### **Contact information**

- mariapb.design@gmail.com
- **1** +34677709274
- Parcelona, Spain
- in @mariapbdesign
- mariaalejandraperez.com

#### **Skills**

Technologies & Tools:

Figma | Sketch | Adobe XD | Invision | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin | Miro | Notion | Maze

Soft skills:

Problem solving | Adaptability | Time management | Empathy | Listening

Hard skills:

Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design

# Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Proficient
German: Beginner
Catalan: Beginner

# Recent Work Experience

03/2021 – present UI Designer

Unblur (Barcelona, Spain)

SaaS provider for front line Emergency services to help them make better, faster data-driven decisions.

- Responsible for the creation of HiFi mockups of new functionalities and enhance already existing ones for all the product platforms (Desktop, tablet, and mobile).
- Maintenance and updating design system (creation and documentation of components).
- · Prototyping and design of micro-interactions.
- · Document Design Guidelines and processes.
- · Performing user acceptance tests.
- Understanding of usability and accessibility in the special context of the company.
- Handover of designs to devs as well as working close with them to guarantee that the visual components look perfectly in code.

## 10/2020 - 02/2021 UX/UI Designer (Freelance project)

FixFirst (Berlin, Germany) [Remote]

SaaS provider for service partners and technicians of home appliances

- Responsible for the creation of HiFi mockups of new functionalities and enhance already existing ones for all the product platforms (Desktop, tablet, and mobile).
- Maintenance and updating design system (creation and documentation of atomic components).
- · Prototyping and design of micro-interactions.
- Document Design Guidelines and processes.
- Performing user acceptance tests.
- Understanding of usability and accessibility in the special context of the company.
- Handover of designs to devs as well as working close with them to guarantee that the visual components look perfectly in code.

#### Education

12/2019 - 06/2020 **UX/UI Designer** 

Ironhack (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2014 - 02/2017 Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona, Spain)

Universidad Simón Bolívar (Caracas, Venezuela)